# **Berkley Olmstead**

5531 S. Adonis, Boise, ID 83716 | 208-871-3882 olms2074@gmail.com | berklev-portfolio.netlifv.app | github.com/Bolmstead

## Summary

Seasoned Senior Full-Stack Software Developer with 3 years experience building SaaS website applications with React, Node, Express, and MongoDB. I am currently leading the development of a SaaS site for Motor Carrier Companies and am building the Frontend, Backend, and API functionality with the MERN stack.

### **Skills**

Languages, Frameworks, and Libraries: Javascript, Typescript, Python, FastAPI, Flask, SQLAlchemy, Node.JS, Express, React, Redux, SQL, Postgres, MySQL, Node-pg, MongoDB, Mongoose, JQuery, AWS, S3, HTML, CSS, Less, JS, Github, Bitbucket, Ant Design, Material-UI, Salesforce: LWCs, Aura, Apex, SOQL, Flows, Controllers, etc.

Other Tools and Skills: CI/CD Pipeline, Agile Methodology, REST API Development, Database Schema Design, Site Deployment Management, Git, Github, Bitbucket, Jira, External REST/SOAP API Integration

## **Experience**

TaxRise - Remote Position

August 2023 - Present

Full-Stack and Salesforce Developer

- Building several React components, Node/Python backend REST API routes, and code to communicate with Postgres/MySQL Databases in order to build web applications currently used by our clients and internally.
- Developing with the Salesforce Platform by creating Salesforce LWC's and Aura Components, building backend Apex classes, dynamic SOQL queries, and strong covered Apex tests.
- Building products such as: a React page and API routes that enable TaxRise Tax Associates to view/add/edit/delete financial records uploaded by our clients, the UI and backend code that enables TaxRise staff to create custom made questions to appear on clients' tax questionnaires dynamically, Salesforce UI and Apex code to enable clients to add/edit/delete their claimed tax assets.
- Utilizing the following tools: React, Node.js, Python, FastAPI, Express, Postgres, MySOL, Agile, Jira, Ant Design, and Salesforce: LWCs, Aura Components, SOQL, Flow Builder, Apex, Controllers, etc.

**TEKware** - Project: SafetyAuditPrep.com - Remote Position

August 2021 - July 2023

- Senior Full-Stack Software Developer
  - Created several React components, backend REST API logic, and MongoDB database architecture for a Motor Carrier Safety Compliance and am currently managing its production site and production database.
  - Created entire UI and necessary backend functionality for the site's following features: Promo Codes, Homepage Dashboard, Password Recovery, Task Assignments, Tractor/Trailer Assignments, Register User and Payment Validation, Automated Invoice Creation with Cron Jobs, Drug Test Requests, and others.
  - Collaborated with our client, building their requested features and advised on any possible issues.
  - Integrated several external REST and SOAP APIs into our code base which include the following: Quest Diagnostics, TazWorks, FMCSA, and Authorize.NET.

Idaho State Tax Commission - Boise, ID

February 2016 - March 2020

Tax Auditor

- Calculated state individual tax deficiencies and prepared audit findings defending my position.
- Handled over 200 audits simultaneously, increasing the state's income by over \$80,000 a year on average.
- Met with taxpayers to communicate tax code ambiguities guiding them to an appropriate plan of action.

### **Education**

#### **Springboard Software Engineering Career Track**

Completion Date: April 2021

Degrees Received: December 2012

- 800+ hours of course material, 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and 4 in-depth portfolio projects.
- Refined skills in front-end and back-end web development, databases, and data structures & algorithms.

**University of Idaho- College of Business and Economics - Moscow, ID** B.S. in Business, Accounting and Finance - Cumulative GPA: 3.45

Certified Public Accountant Exam - Passed all 4 sections of exam